Preliminary Inventory to the James Ford Bell Papers, 1917-1930
Hoover Institution Archives
James Ford Bell Papers,
1917-1930
57003
Bell, James Ford, 1879-1961
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, diaries, reports, financial statements, and photographs, relating to the U.S. Food Administration and the 1928 Herbert Hoover political campaign in Minnesota. Correspondents include Herbert Hoover and Rudolph Lee.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
United States. Food Administration.; Presidents--United States--Election--1928.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Food question.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.; Minnesota--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Lee, Rudolph.
Biography
American business executive; chairman, Milling Division, U.S. Food Administration, 1917-1918.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, diaries, reports, financial statements, and photographs, relating to the United States Food Administration and the 1928 Herbert Hoover political campaign in Minnesota. Correspondents include Herbert Hoover and Rudolph Lee.
Container List
- Printed matter: Report of ETA Mission to Poland, 1919-1922; Supplement to Grain and Flour Statistics during the War, 1920; ARA Bulletin, 1923 September (Box 1., Folder 1)
- Articles, pamphlets, and miscellany by and about Herbert Hoover and about the U.S. Food Administration, 1918-1947 (Folder 2)
- Correspondence between Herbert Hoover and James Ford Bell, 1917-1921 (Folder 3)
- Overseas trip, 1918 July-October (Folder 4)
- Overseas trip - Germany (Folder 5)
- Overseas trip - Central Europe (Folder 6)
- Overseas trip - "Pact of Rome" (Folder 7)
- Overseas trip - France and England (Folder 8)
- Overseas trip - Reports (confidential) (Folder 9)
- Overseas trip - Russia (Folder 10)
- Overseas trip - Italy (Folder 11)
- Print depicting members of the Milling Division of the U.S. Food Administration, ca. 1918 (Folder 12)
- Political correspondence relating mainly to Herbert Hoover's 1928 campaign, particularly in Minnesota, 1928-1930 (Box 2.)
- Diaries of James Ford Bell, 1917-1918 (Box 3.)